Guide to the Chester C. Platt papers, 1869-1934
Platt, Chester C. papers, 1869-1934
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Chester C. Platt papers, 1869-1934.
195
Chester C. Platt
8 cubic ft.
Letters, clippings, pamphlets, financial records and newspapers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Copies of a series of articles written by Platt for the Batavia Times called Human Behavior, which covered a variety of subjects from politics to travel; also included are editorials, articles submitted to other newspapers, speeches, correspondence, and other documents pertaining to Platt's numerous interests. The political correspondents include William Sulzer and Franklin D. Roosevelt. Documents pertaining to the operation of a drugstore. Newspapers include letters pertaining to the three papers with which Platt was associated. Historical documents concerning the Ithaca Unitarian Church, a suit brought against the Forest City Printing Company, some early letters, and accounts. Also, miscellaneous pamphlets, broadsides, and correspondence.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Chester Platt operated a drugstore in Ludlowville and later Ithaca, New York. He became successively proprietor of the ITHACA DEMOCRAT, the BATAVIA TIMES, and the Madison WISCONSIN LEADER. He served as secretary to New York Governor William Sulzer, and was a prominent figure in Democratic state and national politics from 1910 to 1920. In Ithaca he was active in the Unitarian Church and in local politics.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are carbon copies of a series of articles written by Platt for the BATAVIA TIMES called Human Behavior, which covered a variety of subjects from politics to travel; also included are editorials, articles submitted to other newspapers, speeches, correspondence, and other documents pertaining to Platt's numerous interests. The political correspondence contains interesting Sulzer letters and some from Franklin D. Roosevelt, then Secretary of the Navy. The drugstore correspondence gives a picture of a small town druggist struggling to pay his bills; prices of articles and statements of accounts are included. Newspapers include letters pertaining to the three papers with which Platt was associated. The local history series contains documents concerning the Ithaca Unitarian Church, a suit brought against the Forest City Printing Company, some early letters, and accounts. Also, miscellaneous pamphlets, broadsides, and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Platt, Chester C.; Roosevelt, Franklin D.(Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Sulzer, William, 1863-1941.; First Unitarian Church (Ithaca, N.Y.); Forest City Printing Company.
Titles:
Ithaca Democrat.; Batavia times.; Wisconsin leader.
Subjects:
Drugstores--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Drugstores--New York (State)--Ludlowville.; Politics, Practical.; Voyages and travel.; Pharmacists.; Politicians.
Places:
Batavia (N.Y.)--History.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--History.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; New York (State)--Politics and government.
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
A. Platt Articles
B. Political Correspondence
C. Drugstore Correspondence
D. Newspapers
E. Miscellaneous Correspondence
F. Local History
G. Pamphlets and Broadsides.
CONTAINER LIST
- Platt Articles
  - 1903-1934 (Box 1)
- Political Correspondence
  - 1875-1914 (Box 2)
  - 1915-1917 (Box 3)
  - 1918-1923 (Box 4)
  - 1923-1928 (Box 5)
  - 1929-1934 (Box 6)
- Drugstore Correspondence
  - 1873-1994 (Box 7)
  - 1895-1930 (Box 8)
  - Undated correspondence (Box 8)
- Newspapers
  - 1902-1915 (Box 8)
  - 1915-1920 (Box 9)
  - 1917-1919 (Box 10)
  - 1920-1921 (Box 11)
  - 1921-1927 (Box 12)
  - 1928-1934 (Box 13)
  - Undated Correspondence (Box 13)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - 1877-1909 (Box 13)
  - 1905-1919 (Box 14)
  - 1920-1928 (Box 15)
  - 1929-1934 (Box 16)
- Local History
  - 1869-1887 (Box 16)
  - 1893-1920 (Box 17)
  - Undated correspondence (Box 17)
- Bound Volumes
  (Volumes 4, 15, 16, 20, and 24 are missing)
  - Memoranda, 1876 (bills owed, etc.) Chester C. Platt, Druggist, Ludlowville, N. Y. (Volume 1)
  - Cash Book, #1, C. C.-Platt, Druggist, Ludlowville, New York May 1875-Dec. 1879 (Volume 2)
  - Inventories for years 1877, 1878, 1880 (Volume 3)
  - Inventory Supplementary to one closing 5th year (1880) (Volume 4)
  - Ledger #1, 1875-Aug. 1877 (Volume 5)
  - Ledger #2, Sept. 1878-Apr., 1880 (Volume 6)
  - Cash Book #3, 1883-1884 (Volume 7)
  - Inventory closing, first year, complete Apr. 30, 1876 (Volume 8)
  - Diary or Journal of notes and observations kept by C. C. Platt, Ludlowville, New York, Dec. 12, 1879-1889 (Volume 9)
  - Day book, 1887-1889 (Volume 10)
  - Accountbook, 1874-1876 (Volume 11)
  - Cash Book, #2, C. C. Platt, Druggist, 1880-1882 (Volume 12)
  - Treasurer's Book of the First Unitarian Society of Ithaca, New York, 1867-1897 (Volume 13)
  - Drug Inventories for close of 8th and 9th year (1883-1884) (Volume 14)
  - Assessment Roll, Town of Ithaca, 1875 (Volume 15)
  - Scrap Book on Tuberculosis Legislation from Mrs. E. H. Cooper, Troy, N. Y. Jan. 3, 1913 to Hon Wm. Sulzer, Governor of New York. (Volume 16)
  - Letters to and from Calvin E. Keach. Re: Chicago Platform Democrats, 1899 (Volume 17)
  - First Unitarian Society of Ithaca, Building Fund Amount, 1893-1895 (Volume 18)
  - Accountbook, Enz and Miller, Wholesale Dealers in School Books, Stationery, & paper, Ithaca, N.Y., 1893. Cornell University Accounts. (Volume 19)
  - Accountbook, Enz & Miller, 1890, 1891, 1892 (Volume 20)
  - Minute book of the N. N. P. Lyceum of Ludlowville, N. Y., 1867-1874 (Volume 21)
  - Ledger #3, C. C. Platt, 1881-1882 (Volume 22)
  - Ledger 5½, C. C. Platt, 1885 (Volume 23)
  - Ledger, C. C. Platt, 1875-1885 (Volume 24)